https://www.linkedin.com/in/caleb-rose https://www.github.com/CalebRose https://calebrose.io

# Caleb Rose

(952) 334-8334

calebrose.mobile@gmail.com

Software Engineer with four years of professional experience providing QA automation and app development for a global manufacturer. Self-motivated and passionate about designing and developing efficient, functional and creative websites. Seeking an opportunity as an engineer which will build on my experience, challenge me, and provide an opportunity for earned career advancement.

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### **Software Engineer**

#### **General Motors**

September 2018 - Present

- Implemented unit test suites using Junit and Mockito libraries, increasing code coverage from 0% to 95%
- Reworked and integrated microservices for hybrid mobile application, allowing plant workers to log and track units, racks, and errors on the plant floor
- Collaborated with client based in Shanghai to upgrade database application providing thorough battery data
- Interfaced with business clients to provide post-launch support through defect fixes and change requests

#### **Software Test Analyst**

#### **General Motors**

**June 2015 - September 2018** 

- Programmed over 300 automation scripts using GM-based selenium framework across three projects covering administrative and plant floor features, decreasing average test time by 70%
- Tracked and fixed defects found in System Integrated testing environment through cooperation with development team, decreasing the downtime in app development between sprints
- Provided training and documentation to team members on using test automation to improve productivity on test coverage

# **Programming Intern**

# **Argo Group International Holdings**

June 2014 - August 2014

- Designed database for underground storage tank data to support underwriters in sales opportunities
- Developed web-application using .NET alongside CIO and director of app development

# **SKILLS**

Proficient: JavaScript, Node.js, React.js, ES6, Git, SQL, Java, MongoDB, REST APIs, HTML/CSS

Familiar: Python, Spring, Express, Sequelize, Selenium, Mockito, Junit, jQuery, Firebase

#### **PROJECTS**

Work Order Wizard App: https://workorderwizard.herokuapp.com

**Github Repository:** <a href="https://github.com/the-warp-zone/WorkOrderWizard">https://github.com/the-warp-zone/WorkOrderWizard</a>

Project Board: https://github.com/the-warp-zone/WorkOrderWizard/projects/1

- Designed to track clients' work orders and invoices for customers
- Developed frontend using ReactJs and React Router libraries
- Utilized Firebase and Context API to provide user authorization and app security
- Secured and stored data using MongoDB

Fast Travel Stocks App: https://fast-travel-stocks-warp.herokuapp.com/

Github Repository: https://github.com/the-warp-zone/FastTravelStocks

Project Board: <a href="https://github.com/the-warp-zone/FastTravelStocks/projects/1">https://github.com/the-warp-zone/FastTravelStocks/projects/1</a>

- Presents users with financial and data on video game publishers in an easy-to-read format
- Coded application to utilize ReactJs library to meet MVC standards
- Deployed application through Heroku and hosted MySQL database through JawsDB

# **EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS**

Austin, Texas University of Texas at Austin

**February 2019 – August 2019** 

Coding Bootcamp - Full Stack Development

Waco, Texas Baylor University

Major: Management Information Systems, Bachelor of Business Administration

August 2011 - May 2015